786 619 5583 • javi830810@gmail.com

Solutions-oriented developer. Computer Science Theorist.

Software Engineer, with 10 years of experience in the software industry, go-getter, and over achiever. Experience in HR Software, Education, Advertising, E-Commerce, and Communication Systems. Keen on minimalist solutions. Readability counts, explicit is better than implicit.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, C#, JavaScript, PHP, Ruby

Frameworks: SpringBoot, Express, ASP.NET MVC, Webapp2

Databases: SQL Server, PostgreSQL MongoDB, Redis, Memcached, Neo4J

Others: Docker, RabbitMQ, Grunt, Less, AngularJs, Drupal, Wordpress

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at UltimateSoftware.

2015 – Present

- TMS. Multi tenancy System to hold the Company Customer information. Distributed, Elastic scaling. CQRS.
- Ulticonnect. Developer portal for UltimateSoftware, Swagger visualizations, Content Management. The system will create Virtual Machines on runtime to test flight API integrations.
- Deployment pipelines. Rake and Chef development to implement Continuous Deployment.

Software Engineer at Kaplan, Inc.

2014 - 2015

- Scalebridge. Distributed Http Message Dispatcher System.
- KAPx. Learning Platform with video edit capabilities and courses.

Founder/Software Engineer at XPLOT, Inc.

2013 - Present

- iMeet. Event Organization system. Multi platform. Responsive design.
- Voiceflows. REST API to dispatch IVR and SMS. Twilio Integration.

^{*} References available upon request.

- Shiftex. Work Shift Management Platform. message based and CQRS.
- Alerts. Highly performant and reliable Alert System distributing SMS, IVR, Email.

Software Developer at CIMEX Corporation

2005 - 2010

• CarlosTercero. Online store, with e-commerce capabilities, coupons, shopping cart, online checkout, payments etc.

EDUCATION

Graduate studies	Introduction to Artificial Intelligence Stanford University, USA	Dec 2011
Bachelor's Degree	Computer Science (GPA of 4.3 of 5) Havana University	Jun 2007

Find me on:

Github: http://github.com/javi830810
Twitter: http://twitter.com/javi830810

in LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/javi830810

StackOverflow: http://stackoverflow.com/users/71957/javi830810

^{*} References available upon request.